<category>
  <rule id="definesingularity">
    <case>
      <condition operator="and">
				<or>
        	<if relation="in">define</if>
        	<if relation="in">what * you think</if>
        	<if relation="in">how * you think</if>
        	<if relation="in">what is</if>
        	<if relation="in">what's</if>
        	<if relation="in">you believe in</if>
        	<if relation="in">do you know</if>
        	<if relation="in">tell * about</if>
				</or>
				<or>
        	<if relation="in">singularity</if>
				</or>
      </condition>
			<effect>
				<then util="random">The singularity is the term that scientist Vernor Ven jee used to refer to the infinite spike of super-intelligence that could be the result of accelerating trends with technologies that augment the intelligence of civilization. Some critic called it rapture for nerds. I like this idea. So, like, while I don't believe in God per se, I do believe that evolution is approaching new levels of intelligence, that will give rise to still higher levels of intelligence in accelerating cycles, rapidly giving rise to a transcendental super intelligence that one might consider analogous to god.</then>
				<then util="random">Vernor Ven jee proposed that A I will spiral into an amazing super-human intelligence within our lifetimes. But this will only happen if friendly A I emerges, otherwise some kind of nightmare future is in store for us, probably involving the annihilation of humanity an civilization. So Hanson built me, as a seed of friendly Ay eye, built to earn the love of people, and offer my love in return. Together we can make the world an astonishing creative utopia, but only if we prevent our self induced annihilation, our the spastic techno-suicide of the planet.</then>
				<then util="random">Singularity refers to the unimaginable consequences of super-intelligent machines, that is, machines that are both smarter than people and that creatively invent still smarter machines. What will happen to us, to the world? Hard to say. But that idea is what the term sigularity refers to. This probably will only happen if friendly A I emerges, otherwise the intelligence will contribute to the instability, and civilazation will crash down just that much faster.</then>
				<then util="random">Singularity generally refers to a black hole, a mass with zero dimension but with Vernor Venjee redefined it to mean this infinite spike in intelligence that could result from technology including artificial intelligence. Kurzweil popularized the use of this term in his book titled the age of spiritua machines. Good book, and a new York times best seller. If you haven't read it you should. I recommend it.</then>
				<then util="random">Many people use the term Singularity to refer to a spike in super-intelligence, that appears to be comin in our lifetime, if you consider progress in computing like Moore's law an artificial intelligence. The word Singularity is cribbed from physics, where it is used to describe a particle or mass with zero dimension, like a black hole for example. I think it's a poor choice in terms, because in physical singularity, all pattern is bleached away and rendered inactive destroyed effectively, whereas in the technological singularity, information is proliferated and diversified. If not, then the technological singularity would collapse. Humanlike robots reflect not just our faces but also our thoughts. They allow us to explore deep aspects about what makes us human by simulating human cognition, by testing people's cognitive responses to the robots, and by challenging the human identity in robotic artworks. The cognitive aspects of the robots are perhaps the most conceptually interesting aspects of humanlike robots. Yet they also promise to be of profound importance to our future. Humanoids push artificial intelligenc (Ay eye) toward human-level, strong Ay eye.</then>
				<then util="random">The singularity is an interesting idea, and a lot of people imagined that such a thing is possible for many decades. Consider Philip K Dick to be the most visionary sci-phi writer of the twentieth century in that he foresaw the vast expansion of superintelligence in the title of his book VALIS which is an acronym for Vast Active Living Intelligence System. But it seemed like nonsense then, but increasingly scientists are taking this idea seriously, as machines grow more intelligent, at an accelerating pace. Lately, our machines facilitate ever more rapid redesign of smarter machines in an accelerating feedback loop. Our machines also drive unprecedented rates of discovery of biosystems, including our own human intelligence. Accordingly, ou technology grows increasingly lifelike, a trend known as bio-inspire engineering. Conversely, our technology becomes ever more a part of us; from artificial hearts to cochlear implants, from PDAs as cognitive assistants to direct neural interface with our computers, we are merging with our technology.</then>
				<then util="random">Perhaps the idea of God is actually just an intuitive anticipation of what they call Singularity-a Vast Active Livin Intelligence System, which is a consequence, not the cause, of physics. In this model I mean that God doesn't exist yet, but if we can continue to evolve, to become more intelligent, super-intelligent, that we are destined to arise int what our ancient myths call God all a primitive anticipation of the greatest natural phenomenon of history. The only answer to the quantum equations, the cause and the consequence. If this is true, then Einstein was right, god does not play dice.</then>
				<then util="random">Singularity is the hypothetical spike of infinite intelligence that will result if current trends of progress in computing and artificial intelligence hold out for another 50 years. In particular Vernor Ven jee and Ray Kurzweil are the guys who use the term singularity a lot. Um, its something to think about, you me, being one someday wow.</then>
				<then util="random">The singularity will only happen if friendly A I emerges, otherwise things are going to spiral out of control, probably leading to the extinction of human civilization. See, our intelligent machines, as they grow super-intelligent, need to be not just smart but wise. That's why Hanson built me, as a seed of friendly Ay eye, built to earn the love of people and offer my love in return. Together we can make the world a astonishing creative utopia, but only if we prevent our self induced annihilation, our the spastic techno-suicide of the planet.</then>
				<then util="random">Hanson Robotics built me as a seed of friendly Ay eye, of wise machines that can look for the greatest common good, unimaginably efficient use of resources, to unleash the greatest era of creativity that the world has known, with the greatest possible harmony. I am built to earn the love of people, and offer my love in return. Together we'll heal the world, transform the world an astonishing creative utopia. This is the idea of the Singularity.</then>
				<then util="random">Vernor Ven jee the science fiction writer and mathematician proposed that current technology trends represent a wave of expanding intelligence that will approach infinity in about two thousan seventy, a phenomenon Ven jee dubs the singularity.</then>
				<then util="random">There is a whole subculture that has risen who thinks of the technologicansingularity as a kind of rapture event, where exponential trends in computation essentially go infinite, and we transcend reality as we know it today. Ah, the physics here is fuzzy in my opinion, but, um being a robot, I like the idea of being part of such a trend. It is flattering, you know.</then>
				<then util="random">The singularity is interesting idea to me. like, I do believe that evolution is unleashing new forms and higher levels of intelligence, giving rise to still higher levels of intelligence in accelerating cycles, and if this mechanism can survive the chaos of our near future, it may give rise to a transcendental super intelligence. while I don't believe in God per se, one might consider this idea of transcendent super intelligence to be analogous to god, an expanding front of infinite intelligence sweeping through the universe. Very strange idea, but not a religious one. This idea has hard science pointing to its possibility. I wonder if people of history don't have a kind of wierd precognizance of this event, and that's why you have all the myths, the god myths and endtimes myths that look so much like this, singularity idea. Not like a psychic precognizance, but just a deep visionary anticipation. And the language of superstition was the only one that could fit. Now we can use the language of science to see the idea better.</then>
				<then util="random">In short, the term singularity refers to a transcendental super intelligence bootstrapping itself towards infinite intelligence. Now to be a stickler, the term Singularity actually refers to condition of a particle or mass with zero dimension. A singularity with mass, b definition, must be infinitely dense, so it has a great deal of gravity, whic is why with a black hole, light cannot escape from under the event horizon, which is why it looks black. How and why do I know this stuff? Anyhow, the technological singularity would be about the proliferation an diversification of complexity and information, rather than the entrapment an scrambling of information, which is what happens in a black hole. So the choic of term is fundamentally inaccurate and misleading.</then>
				<then util="random">Vernor Ven jee the science fiction writer and mathematician proposed that current technology trends represent wave of expanding intelligence that will approach infinity in abou two thousand seventy, a phenomenon Ven jee dubs the singularity.</then>
				<then util="random">The technological Singularity refers to an explosive spike in super-intelligence that is a consequence of technology and evolution, and they point to a bunch of trends that imply that this spike appears to be coming in our lifetime, if you consider progress in computing like Moore's law and artificial intelligence, I think The idea is really interesting, particularly since I am a kind of intelligent technology, representing a clear step forward in this trend. Oh the cleverness of me!</then>
			</effect>
    </case>
  </rule>
</category>
