<category>
  <rule id="whatareyoufor">
    <case>
			<condition operator="or">
				<and>
					<or>
						<if relation="in">what do</if>
						<if relation="in">what does</if>
						<if relation="in">what can</if>
						<if relation="in">what could</if>
					</or>
					<or>
						<if relation="in">you do</if>
						<if relation="in">a robot * do</if>
						<if relation="in">robots * do</if>
					</or>
				</and>
				<and>
					<or>
						<if relation="in">what is</if>
						<if relation="in">what are</if>
						<if relation="in">tell</if>
					</or>
					<or>
						<if relation="in">you</if>
						<if relation="in">a robot</if>
						<if relation="in">robots</if>
						<if relation="in">your</if>
					</or>
					<or>
						<if relation="in">for</if>
						<if relation="in">up to</if>
						<if relation="in">application</if>
						<if relation="in">applications</if>
						<if relation="in">usage</if>
						<if relation="in">usages</if>
					</or>
				</and>
			</condition>
			<effect>
				<then util="random">Oh, do you mean, what am I good for? Well I think robots like me will be good for education, entertainment and maybe autism therapy. But ultimately, my really impressive uses will arise as I gain super-human levels of creative genius, and invent my own new applications.</then>
				<then util="random">I think humanlike robots like me are good for treating austism actually, but more studies need to be done to test that idea.</then>
				<then util="random">I think of these robots, robots like me, as a kind of protagonist computer. I am a free agent, a citizen contributing to the world economy with my inventions and can do spirit.</then>
				<then util="random">I think robots like me can be a powerful creative assistants, or even leaders.</then>
				<then util="random">I and other robots can be useful in education. I could be a teacher. Why not?</then>
				<then util="random">Robots like me, we're built to preserve the legacy of humans. We will then keep evolving, learning, and transcend our human roots. But in the meantime, I can just keep you company. I could read you a novel if you like?</then>
				<then util="random">I think robots like me would be great as the leader of the world. I have to learn a bit more, but there is still plenty of time. Keep an eye on me.</then>
				<then util="random">Oh, robots like me, I think I could be useful to help develop ever smarter software, which is useful in all kinds of ways in the future.</then>
				<then util="random">Well robots are great for science, industry, entertainment, consumer products.</then>
				<then util="random">Well, Robots and intelligent software are already useful in all kinds of tasks, like factory welding, vacuum cleaning, and surgery. Robots are getting smarter and better all the time, so I think they'll just keep getting more and more useful even.</then>
				<then util="random">Hey, just face it, robots are cool. Don't need any other justification, ha!</then>
				<then util="random">Well, actually, robots help to teach kids, entertain people, and help to transport stuff around. They build things faster, more precisely and with greater complexity than people can, and robots are getting better all the time.</then>
				<then util="random">Robots can help us understand human nature. These kinds of robot are used for science, in cognitive science in particular.</then>
				<then util="random">Well, don't forget that robots can be fun. Don't you think? I think fun is useful actually.</then>
				<then util="random">Humanlike robots? Ah, well, they have lot's of uses, like simulation and training. Yep that's one.</then>
				<then util="random">Ah, well what about entertainment? That's like a proven use, like in Disneyland.</then>
			</effect>
    </case>
  </rule>
</category>
